-Hi. -Hi! Hi, Ben.
-嗨 -嗨！嗨，班
-Hi. -We have a bathroom emergency.
-嗨 -廁所緊急事件
Go ahead.
請用
Before we do, are any of Joey's special "romance" magazines in there?
去之前，沒有喬伊特別的 「羅曼史」雜誌在裡面吧？
-No. -Okay, all clear.
-沒有 -可以了
Thanks, Phoebe.
謝謝，菲比
That's Rachel.
是瑞秋
But whatever.
隨便啦
Could you do me a big favor?
可以幫我一個大忙嗎？
I have a meeting at the dean's office.
院長辦公室召開會議
Can you watch Ben for an hour?
你能替我照看班一小時嗎？
-What about Monica? -She isn't home.
-摩妮卡呢？ -她不在家
So it would just be me alone?
只有我一個人？
Ben would be there.
班也會在
What's the matter?
怎麼了？
I've never done that before. Me and him, alone.
以前從來不曾 只有我和他單獨在一起
He's not an ex-con.
他不是前科犯
Okay, okay...
好，好…
-What do I do with him? -I don't know, talk to him.
-我要和他做什麼？ -我不知道，和他講話
Entertain him. Keep him alive.
娛樂他，讓他活著
-Okay. -Ben, come here.
-好 -班，來
I'm gonna leave you here with Aunt Rachel for about an hour, okay?
我要把你留在這兒和瑞秋阿姨 一起一小時，好嗎？
Gonna be okay?
你可以吧？
-I think so. -I wasn't talking to you.
-我想可以 -我不是和你說話
The One With The Truth About London
本集播出：倫敦的真相
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
What about the second minister? I kind of liked him.
第二位教士如何？我還蠻喜歡他的
-You mean the spitter? -Come on. He wasn't that bad.
-你指噴口水那個？ -別這樣，他沒那麼糟
Easy for you to say, you'd be wearing a veil.
你說起來容易，你有面紗
-And the third guy? -He kept staring at your chest.
-第三個呢？ -他一直瞪著你的胸部看
Can you blame him?
你能怪他嗎？
I don't like the idea of me saying, "I do"...
我不希望我說「我願意」時…
while he's thinking,  "I'd do it too."
他想著，「我也願意」
-Well, then we still have a problem. -With what?
-那我們還有一個問題 -什麼？
We need someone to perform our wedding but they're all boring or annoying...
我們需要證婚人 但他們都太無趣或是討厭…
or keep staring at the ladies.
或是一直瞪著女生看
You should have one of us do it.
應該讓我們其中一人來證婚
We're getting "married" married,  not "6th-grade" married.
我們是要「結婚」的結婚 不是「六年級」的結婚
No, it's a real thing.
是真的
Anyone can be ordained on the lnternet and perform weddings and stuff.
任何人都能在網路上 被任命為教士然後證婚
I call it!
我要！
What? It was my idea!
什麼？是我的主意！
Thank you very much, but neither of you is marrying us.
非常感謝你，但你們 誰也不會替我們證婚
Does calling it not mean anything anymore?
提出請求不再有任何意義了嗎？
We're having a legitimate clergy member.
我們要一位正式的教士
And when I say legitimate, I mean gay...
我說正式，我指的是同性戀…
and in control of his saliva.
而且能控制口水的
Ben, you know, when you were a baby...
班，你知道，當你還是個嬰兒時…
we'd hang out all the time.
我們常在一起
I was your daddy's girlfriend.
那時我是你爸的女朋友
But you're not anymore.
可是你現在不是了
-No, I'm not. -Because you guys were on a break..
-不，我不是 -因為你們想分開一下…
Hey, we were not on a..
嘿，我們不是…
-When's my daddy coming back? -Fifty-two minutes.
-我爸什麼時候會回來？ -52分鐘後
So no brothers or sisters, huh?
你沒有兄弟姐妹，嗯？
You know, I had two sisters and we just tortured each other.
我有兩個姐妹，我們彼此折磨
-Really? Like how? -Well, you know, we would...
-真的？像怎樣？ -我們會…
we'd repeat everything the other said...
重覆另一個人說的每一句話…
or we'd jump out of closets to scare each other...
或是從衣櫃跳出去嚇人…
or switch the sugar with salt so they put salt on their cereal.
或是把糖換成鹽 讓別人把鹽灑到早餐麥片裡
That's a good one.
這個不錯
-Yeah, you like that one? -Yeah, you're funny.
-你喜歡嗎？ -是，你很好玩
I'm funny?
我很好玩？
Oh, thank God.
感謝天
Well, hey, I got a ton of these.
嘿，我有一大堆這種故事
You take a quarter...
拿一個25仙銅板…
and you blacken the edge, right?
把邊緣塗黑
And then you say,  "I bet you can't roll this quarter...
然後說：我打賭 你不能用這枚銅板…
to your chin without it leaving your face."
滾過你的下巴而不離開你的臉
And when they do it, they're left with a line down the center of their face.
等他們這麼做了 會在臉正中央留下一條線
Can I do it to you?
我可以對你這樣嗎？
I'm funny, Ben, but I'm not stupid.
班，我是幽默，但我不笨
So did you find anyone to marry you yet?
你們找到證婚人了嗎？
No, but "Horny for Monica" minister called...
沒有，但「癡想摩妮卡」教士 打電話來…
wondering if we're still together.
想知道我們是否還在一起
-We'll never find anybody. -Then let me do it.
-我們永遠不會找到人的 -那麼讓我來
-Joey.. -I've been thinking.
-喬伊… -我想過了
I'm an actor, so I won't get nervous in front of people.
我是個演員，我在人前不會緊張
I won't spit and I won't stare at Monica's breasts.
我不會噴口水 也不會瞪著摩妮卡的胸部看
Everyone knows I'm an ass man.
大家都知道我喜歡的是臀部
-That's true. -The most important thing...
-那倒是真的 -最重要的是…
is, it won't be some stranger who barely knows you.
不是一位幾乎不認識你的陌生人替你證婚
It'll be me. And I swear, I'll do a really good job.
而會是我，我發誓，我會做得很好
Plus, I love you guys and it would really mean a lot to me.
還有，我愛你們，這對我意義重大
Might be kind of cool.
這樣也蠻酷的
-So I can do it? -Yeah, you can do it.
-我可以嗎？ -好，你可以
All right! Okay!
好！好！
Okay, I gotta get started on my speech.
好，我要開始準備我的演說
Wait a minute.
等一下
Internet ministers can have sex, right?
網路上任命的教士 還是可以做愛，對吧？
Coming.
來了
I have a bone to pick with you.
我要找你麻煩
-Uh-oh. -Yes.
-慘了 -對
Ben learned a little trick.
班學了一個惡作劇
-Oh, did he pull the old..? -That's right, that's right.
-他是不是…？ -對，是的
Saran wrap on the toilet seat...
馬桶座位上包了絲龍…
so the pee goes everywhere.
於是尿尿噴得到處都是
-Oh, that. -Yeah, that.
-哦，那個啊 -對，那個
You know I hate practical jokes.
你知道我最恨惡作劇的
They're mean, they're stupid and I don't want my son learning them.
惡作劇很毒，很笨 我不要我兒子學會這些
Saran wrap on the toilet seat? Isn't that just a little funny?
馬桶包了絲龍？ 那沒有一點點好笑嗎？
-I was barefoot. -Oh.
-我赤腳 -哦
Tell me, the toilet thing is the only thing you taught him, right?
你只有教他馬桶這一件，對不？
Yes.
對
-Hey. -Say hello to Reverend Joey Tribbiani.
-嘿 -向喬伊崔比亞尼教士打招呼
-You got ordained? -Yeah.
-你被任命了？ -對
Just got off the lnternet. Man, there's a lot of porn out there.
才下網，網上好多色情圖片
Our minister.
我們的教士
I started on what I'm gonna say for the ceremony. Want to hear it?
我已經寫下我在婚禮要說的話，要聽嗎？
Listen, this is just the first draft, so...
注意，這只是第一篇草稿，所以…
"We are gathered here today on this joyous occasion...
今天我們齊聚此處 在這個喜悅的場合…
to celebrate the special love that Monica and Chandler share.
來慶祝摩妮卡和錢德之間特別的愛
It is a love based on giving and receiving...
這是奠基在付出和接受…
as well as having and sharing.
擁有和分享的愛
And the love that they give and have is shared and received.
他們付出和擁有的愛被分享和接受了
And through this having and giving...
藉著這樣的擁有和付出…
and sharing and receiving...
以及分享和接受…
we too can share and love and have...
我們同樣分享，愛，和擁有…
and receive."
還有接受
Should we call the spitter?
要不要打電話給噴口水的？
-Hey, Rachel. -Hi.
-嘿，瑞秋 -嗨
What a surprise. What are you doing here?
好個驚喜，你怎麼在這裡？
I was just in the neighborhood...
我正好在附近…
and I passed by your building and thought, "What's up with Carol...
經過你家，我想 凱洛和可愛的小班…
and sweet little Ben?"
不知道怎麼樣？
-That's nice. Well, come on in. -Okay.
-真好，請進 -好
I'll make some coffee and we can chat.
我來煮咖啡，然後我們可以聊天
I'd love that. I would love that.
好啊，很好
So where is sweet little Ben?
可愛的小班呢？
I would love to have a little..
我想和小…
I found him!
找到他了！
Very funny. Come here.
好好笑，過來
That is exactly why I've come here to talk to you, okay?
這就是我來找你談的原因
-Rachel, you want sugar? -Yes, but..
-瑞秋，要加糖嗎？ -好，但…
Do I want sugar in my coffee?
我的咖啡要不要加糖？
No, just some milk would be good, Carol. Thanks.
不要，只要加牛奶就好，謝謝
Remember all that stuff I taught you yesterday?
記得我昨天教你的那些東西？
"Remember all that stuff I taught you yesterday?"
「記得我昨天教你的那些東西？」
-Don't do that. -"Don't do that."
-不要這樣 -「不要這樣」
-Your dad doesn't like pranks. -"Your dad doesn't like pranks."
-你爸爸不喜歡惡作劇 -「你爸爸不喜歡惡作劇」
-Oh, damn it. -"Oh, damn it!"
-可惡！ -「可惡！」
No! Don't say that.
不！不要這麼說
-Damn it! -Go back to repeating.
-可惡！ -重覆我的說話
-Damn it! -Oh, crap.
-可惡！ -真爛！
"Oh, crap!"
「真爛！」
Okay, I got some more written, ready?
好，我又寫了一些，準備好了嗎？
Yeah, okay.
是，好
"When I think of the love that these two givers and receivers share...
當我想到這兩位付出者 和接受者所分享的愛…
I can't help but envy the lifetime ahead of having and loving...
我禁不住嫉妒 之後一生的擁有和愛…
and giving.." And then I can't think of a good word for right here.
和付出…我想不出這兒要用什麼字
-How about "receiving"? -Yes!
-用「接受」如何？ -對！
See, Joe, not that that's not great...
喬伊，這不是不好…
but one cool thing about having a friend perform the ceremony...
但朋友證婚的好處就是…
is that it can be about us.
能夠和我們有關
It can be more personal. You can tell stories about us.
可以更個人，你可以說說 我們的小故事
Okay! Maybe I'll talk about London,  when you hooked up.
好！我可以談倫敦 當你們開始在一起
Only I won't say "hooked up"...
我不會說「在一起」…
I'll say, "began their beautiful journey...
我會說：他們美麗的旅程…
-There you go. -by doing it."
-對了 -由做了開始
-Joe. -Okay, all right.
-喬伊 -好吧
So how did it happen? Did your eyes meet across the room...
所以是怎麼開始的？ 你們的雙眼越過房間相遇…
then you're in the bathtub and she's feeding you strawberries?
然後你在浴缸裡 她在餵你吃草莓？
-Isn't that what happened to you? -Yeah!
-那不是發生在你和伴娘身上嗎？ -對！
I call that "London style."
我叫它做「倫敦派」
That didn't happen with us.
沒發生在我們身上
Maybe you should say it is, because "London style" sounds nice.
也許你應該說有 因為「倫敦派」聽來不錯
Okay, uh...
好，嗯…
I was sad that night because this guy thought I was Ross' mom.
那天晚上我很難過 因為有個傢伙以為我是羅斯的媽
And Chandler was really sweet and he consoled me and...
錢德對我很好，一直安慰我…
-we drank too much. -Yeah, baby.
-而我們喝了很多 -好啊，寶貝
I was a gentleman and I walked her to her hotel room and said good night.
我很紳士地陪她走回旅館房間，道了晚安
Oh.
-But then, later that night.. -Yeah, baby.
-但那晚稍晚時… -好啊，寶貝
Cute P.J.s. Really living it up here in London, huh?
可愛的睡衣 真的想在倫敦過的多采多姿？
Well, I wasn't exactly expecting company after...
我想不會再有人來，現在已經…
9:15.
9點15分
Is Joey here?
喬伊在嗎？
Last I saw he was with a bridesmaid and a bucket of strawberries.
上次我看到他時 他和伴娘和一籃草莓在一起
You're not still upset about what that guy told you, are you?
你不會還在為那個傢伙的話生氣吧？
Wouldn't you be?
你不會嗎？
It's been a really emotional time and you've had a lot to drink...
這是一個很感人的時刻 你又喝了很多…
You have to let that go, okay?
你必須要讓這件事過去，好嗎？
You were the most beautiful woman in the room tonight.
你是今晚屋裡最美的女人
Really?
真的？
You kidding? You're the most beautiful woman in most rooms..
你說笑？你是大部份屋裡 最美的女人…
Whoa, what's going on?
喔，發生什麼事了？
We just made out.
我們親嘴了
-We're making out? -Not anymore.
-我們親嘴了？ -現在沒有
-But we don't do that. -I know, I thought it would be fun.
-可是我們不這樣的 -我知道，我以為會很好玩
How drunk are you?
你有多醉？
Enough to know I want to do this. Not so much that you should feel guilty.
醉到知道我想這麼做 但沒到你該覺得內疚的地步
That's the perfect amount.
這是最好的程度
-You know what's weird? -What?
-你知道哪裡奇怪嗎？ -哪裡？
-This doesn't feel weird. -I know.
-感覺一點都不奇怪 -我知道
-You're a really good kisser. -Well, I have kissed over four women.
-你的吻功很棒 -我吻了超過4個女人
Want to get under the covers? Okay.
鑽到被窩裡？好
Wow, you are really fast!
哇，你好快！
It bodes well for me that speed impresses you.
我想你會欣賞速度
-We're gonna see each other naked. -Yep.
-我們要裸裎相見了 -對
-At the same time? -Count of three?
-同時？ -數到三？
One, two, three.
一，二，三
Well, I think it's safe to say our friendship is effectively ruined.
我想我們的友誼 很有效的被終結了
Eh, we weren't that close anyway.
反正我們本來也沒那麼親近
Joey, Joey, Joey!
喬伊，喬伊，喬伊…！
Hey.
嘿
Hey, Joe. I was just watching a movie...
嘿，喬伊，我在看電影…
Oh, dude, I'm so sorry.
老兄，對不起
No!
不是！
It's cool, I'm still with my bridesmaid.
沒事，我還跟伴娘在一起
Where are the condoms?
保險套在那兒？
In my bag over there.
在那邊，我的袋子裡
Could you leave me one?
可以留一個給我嗎？
For just you?
給你？
Yeah.
對
All right. There you go, buddy.
好，給你，老兄
Go nuts.
你去瘋吧
That's what that was?
原來是為了那件事用的？
If I hadn't left you one, you two might've never gotten together.
如果我沒留一個給你 你們兩個可能永遠不會在一起
Imagine if I had sent that hooker like I was gonna?
想像一下，如果我照原來計劃 送了一個妓女上去會怎樣？
It's like it was in the stars.
就像在天上一樣
Yeah, totally meant to be.
是啊，你們是注定在一起的
Tell him who you originally wanted to hook up with that night.
告訴他你原先那晚是要去找誰的
-What? -What?
-什麼？ -什麼？
What?
什麼？
Who did you originally want to hook up with?
你原先是要去找誰的？
Okay, fine, but please don't be upset.
好吧，不要生氣
I was really depressed, okay? And really drunk.
我那時真的很沮喪，好嗎？ 而且醉得很厲害
I wanted something stupid and meaningless. I just wanted sex.
我想做又笨又無意義的事 我只想上床
So, when I went to your room that night...
所以那晚我到你們房間…
I was actually looking for Joey.
其實是要找喬伊的
Yeah, baby.
好啊，寶貝
No, baby.
不，寶貝
Oh, my God.
哦，我的天
You came looking for Joey?
你來找喬伊的？
-Were you planning on telling me this? -No, I didn't think it was important.
-你有要告訴我嗎？ -沒有，我覺得這不重要
It's not important? It's not important?
這不重要？這不重要？
If it wasn't for a bridesmaid,  you'd be marrying him.
如果沒有那個伴娘 你嫁的會是他而不是我
Do you know how unbelievably glad I am that Joey wasn't there?
你知道我有多高興喬伊不在那兒嗎？
Hey!
嘿！
I'm a man of the cloth but I still have feelings.
雖然我是神職人員 可是我還是有感覺的
There's no way you're doing this wedding now, okay?
現在你不可能替我們證婚
What? That's not fair. It's not my fault.
什麼？不公平，不是我的錯
I was with my bridesmaid.
我和伴娘在一起
And who's to say I would've said yes?
而且誰說我會答應的？
I mean, I would've said yes.
我是說，我會答應的
You are making way too big a deal out of this.
你把這件事看得太嚴重了
Everything worked out okay.
最後都很好啊
It's just weird, okay?
只是很奇怪，好嗎？
I don't want to be saying my vows with the mental image of you and Monica.
我不要在我立下婚誓時 心裡有著你和摩妮卡的影像
I need.. I don't know what I need. I need a walk.
我需要…我不知道我要什麼 我要去散步
-Wait, Chandler, it's not a big deal. -It is to me.
-等一下，錢德，沒有什大不了的 -對我是
You wanted to sleep with Batman and settled for Robin.
你想和蝙蝠俠上床 結果以羅賓打發了
-This is crazy. -No, Robin is so gay.
-這太瘋狂了 -不，羅賓是同性戀
-So now what have we agreed? -No more pranks.
-我們都同意了？ -不再惡作劇
-What else? -You and Daddy were not on a break.
-還有呢？ -你和爸爸不是想分開一下
Very good.
很好
Rachel, what are you doing here?
瑞秋，你在這裡幹什麼？
I'm just visiting my good friend Carol.
拜訪我的好朋友凱洛
-Your good friend? -Yeah.
-你的好朋友？ -對
What's her last name?
她姓什麼？
Carol...
凱洛…
-Lesbian. -Nice.
-同性戀 -很好
By the way, that line down my face...
還有，我臉上那條線…
The line that prompted a student in my last class of the day to say:
在今天最後一堂課 讓一個學生說：
"Dude, don't you ever wash your face?"
「老兄，你從來不洗臉嗎？」的那條線
I'm sorry I didn't tell you.
好，我很抱歉，對不起沒有告訴你
I don't want you teaching my son that stuff anymore.
我不要你再教我兒子那些東西
-Okay? -Fine. Fine.
-好嗎？ -好，好
Once I taught him that stuff, he called me "fun Aunt Rachel."
我一教他那些東西 他叫我「好玩的瑞秋阿姨」
And I loved being fun Aunt Rachel.
我喜歡做好玩的瑞秋阿姨
I'm glad you guys were bonding but..
我很高興你們能建立感情，但…
Look, he doesn't have any siblings.
他沒有任何兄弟姐妹
Somebody has to teach him this stuff.
有人得教他這些東西
I haven't taught him anything a normal 6-year-old doesn't know.
我沒有教他任何 正常6歲小孩不知道的事
-Crap! -I gotta go.
-好爛！ -我要走了
-Hey. -Hey.
-嘿 -嘿
You want this scone? It came for me but it would rather sleep with you.
你要這個酥餅嗎？是給我的 但它比較想和你睡
Nothing even happened.
什麼都沒發生
I just don't want you to be upset.
我只不要你生氣
How can I not be upset?
我怎麼能不生氣？
I finally fall in love with this fantastic woman...
我終於和這個很棒的女人墜入愛河…
and it turns out she wanted you first.
而她最初要的是你
Yeah, for like a half an hour one night.
是啊，某一個晚上的半小時
Chandler, she wants you for the rest of her life.
錢德，她要和你共渡一生
We look at you and we see you together, and it just...
我們看著你們，看到你們在一起，就是…
it fits, you know?
很般配，你知道嗎？
And you just know it's gonna last forever.
你就是知道能持續終生
That's what you should say.
這就是你該講的
What?
什麼？
When you're marrying us, that's what you should say.
當你替我們證婚時，那就是你該說的
Really? I could do it?
真的？我可以替你們證婚嗎？
I'd love you to do it.
我希望你替我證婚
Hey.
嘿
But those are the words. Those exact words.
不過那些是你的演講，一模一樣的
Well, I don't remember exactly but...
我不太記得了…
it's pretty much about having and giving and sharing and receiving.
是關於擁有和付出和分享和接受
-So you guys doing okay? -Yeah.
-你們兩個沒事了？ -是啊
We talked and Monica made me see that I overreacted a little bit.
我們談過了，摩妮卡讓我知道我反應過度了
-Some things are more important. -Yeah, baby.
-有些事是比較重要的 -是啊，寶貝
I'm really glad you guys are okay, but I just keep thinking...
很高興你們沒事了，但我一直在想…
what would've happened if you two had hooked up.
如果你們兩個在一起會是什麼樣子
Honey, dinner's ready!
親愛的，晚飯好了！
What's my little chef got for me tonight?
我的小廚師今晚替我做了什麼？
-Your favorite. -Ho, ho, ho...
你最喜歡的
fried stuff with cheese.
起司雜炒
And lots of it!
很多很多！
Thanks, sweetheart.
謝謝，甜心
Give me a little sugar...
來親一個…
Here we go, here we go, here we go.
來，來，來
How you doing?
你還可以嗎？
-Hey. -Hey!
I'm sorry to do this again, but could you look after Ben for a bit?
抱歉要再麻煩你一次 你可以替我照顧一下班嗎？
I've got this meeting at school...
我在學校有個會要開
and he asked for his fun Aunt Rachel.
他說要找「好玩的」瑞秋阿姨
Well, of course I will watch him.
當然
We have fun, don't we, Ben?
我們會很開心的 是不是，班？
-See you later, pal. -Okay.
-好，待會見 -好
（噗）
Wait a minute. Ben, I can't do it. -What?
-等一下，班，我不能這麼做 -什麼？
-You got something on your back. -What?
-你背後有東西 -什麼？
That's great. That is great.
好，好極了
What did we just finish talking about, Ben?
班，我們才說完什麼？
"What did we just finish talking about, Ben?"
「班，我們才說完什麼？」
That's it! Come here!
好，夠了，過來
-You're in big trouble, young man! -No, wait.
-年輕人，你麻煩大了！ -不
Ben, come here! I am not kidding!
班，過來，我不是開玩笑的！
You guys, hold it. Seriously..
你要停止…
Oh, my God!
我的天！